<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DK's page</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/</link><atom:link href="https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>DK's page</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>DK's page</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/</link></image><item><title>Example Talk</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/talk/example-talk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/talk/example-talk/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Click on the &lt;strong>Slides&lt;/strong> button above to view the built-in slides feature.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create&lt;/strong> slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Slides&lt;/em>&lt;/a> feature and link using &lt;code>slides&lt;/code> parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Upload&lt;/strong> an existing slide deck to &lt;code>static/&lt;/code> and link using &lt;code>url_slides&lt;/code> parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Embed&lt;/strong> your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shortcodes&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Further event details, including &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">page elements&lt;/a> such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beyond classical dimensionality reduction techniques</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/dimensionality_reduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/dimensionality_reduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dimensionality reduction is a technique used in machine learning to reduce the number of features in a dataset. This can help to improve the performance of machine learning models by reducing the amount of noise and redundancy in the data, as well as making the data more computationally efficient to process. Some of the modern methods of dimensionality reduction include:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Principal Component Analysis (PCA): PCA is a popular technique used to reduce the dimensionality of a dataset by identifying the principal components that explain the most variance in the data. It works by projecting the data onto a new set of orthogonal axes, with each axis representing a principal component.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>t-Distributed Stochastic Neighbor Embedding (t-SNE): t-SNE is a nonlinear dimensionality reduction technique that is particularly effective for visualizing high-dimensional data. It works by mapping the high-dimensional data points to a low-dimensional space, while preserving the pairwise distances between the data points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Autoencoders: Autoencoders are neural networks that can be used for unsupervised learning and dimensionality reduction. They work by compressing the input data into a lower-dimensional representation, and then reconstructing the original input from this compressed representation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Non-negative Matrix Factorization (NMF): NMF is a matrix factorization technique that can be used for dimensionality reduction and feature extraction. It works by factorizing a non-negative matrix into two non-negative matrices, where the resulting factors can be interpreted as a lower-dimensional representation of the original data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UMAP (Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection): UMAP is a newer technique for dimensionality reduction that is gaining popularity. It works by constructing a low-dimensional representation of the data that preserves both local and global structure, making it particularly useful for clustering and visualization tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These modern methods of dimensionality reduction offer a range of options to choose from, and selecting the most appropriate technique for a particular dataset depends on the nature of the data and the specific goals of the analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linear unmixing models on hyperspectral data</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/spectral_unmixing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/spectral_unmixing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Linear unmixing is a popular technique used for analyzing hyperspectral data. Hyperspectral imaging is a remote sensing technique that captures the electromagnetic radiation reflected from the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface across hundreds of narrow spectral bands. Linear unmixing is used to extract information about the different materials present in the scene based on their spectral signatures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The linear unmixing model assumes that each pixel in the hyperspectral image can be represented as a linear combination of the spectral signatures of the materials present in that pixel. In other words, the pixel&amp;rsquo;s spectrum is a weighted sum of the spectra of the constituent materials. This model is expressed mathematically as:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ð¼(Î») = ð‘†(Î»)ð´&lt;/p>
&lt;p>where ð¼(Î») is the observed spectrum at wavelength Î», ð‘†(Î») is the matrix of spectral signatures for the materials of interest, and ð´ is the abundance matrix that represents the proportion of each material present in the pixel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The linear unmixing process involves estimating the abundance matrix ð´ for each pixel in the image. This is typically done using optimization techniques such as least squares, non-negative least squares, or constrained least squares. Once the abundance matrix is estimated, the abundance maps can be generated for each material, providing information about the spatial distribution of the different materials in the scene.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linear unmixing is widely used in applications such as mineral mapping, vegetation analysis, and urban land-use classification, among others. It is a powerful tool for extracting information from hyperspectral data and can provide valuable insights into the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface and its composition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Optimization Methods for Financial Index Tracking</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/index_tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/index_tracking/</guid><description>&lt;p>Financial index tracking is a popular investment strategy that involves investing in a portfolio of securities that mirrors the composition and performance of a particular financial index, such as the S&amp;amp;P 500 or the Dow Jones Industrial Average. The goal of index tracking is to achieve returns that closely match the performance of the chosen index, which is considered to be a benchmark for the overall market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Index tracking is typically achieved through passive investing, which involves buying and holding the constituent securities of the index in proportion to their weights in the index. This approach allows investors to benefit from the growth of the overall market without having to make individual stock selections.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several advantages to index tracking. First, it offers broad exposure to a diversified portfolio of securities, which can reduce the risk of losses due to individual stock performance. Second, it typically has lower fees and expenses compared to actively managed funds, which can improve the overall returns for investors. Finally, it is a simple and transparent investment strategy that is easy to understand and implement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Semantic Segmentation of Remote Sensing Images</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/unet_remote_sensing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/unet_remote_sensing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Semantic segmentation in remote sensing refers to the process of segmenting an image obtained from a remote sensing platform (such as a satellite or drone) into different regions or objects based on their semantic meaning. This involves assigning each pixel in the image to a particular class or category, such as vegetation, water, buildings, roads, and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has many applications, such as land cover classification, urban planning, environmental monitoring, and disaster management. It can be performed using a variety of techniques, including supervised and unsupervised machine learning algorithms, deep learning models, and image processing techniques.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some popular deep learning models used for semantic segmentation in remote sensing include U-Net, FCN, SegNet, and DeepLab. These models use convolutional neural networks (CNNs) to extract features from the input image and then apply a decoder to generate a pixel-wise segmentation map.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Time-series forecasting models based on DARTs</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/time_series_dart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/time_series_dart/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Conformal Prediction and Distribution-Free Uncertainty Quantification</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/conformal_prediction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/conformal_prediction/</guid><description>&lt;p>Black-box machine learning models are now routinely used in high-risk settings, like medical diagnostics, which demand uncertainty quantification to avoid consequential model failures. Conformal prediction is a user-friendly paradigm for creating statistically rigorous uncertainty sets/intervals for the predictions of such models. Critically, the sets are valid in a distribution-free sense: they possess explicit, non-asymptotic guarantees even without distributional assumptions or model assumptions. One can use conformal prediction with any pre-trained model, such as a neural network, to produce sets that are guaranteed to contain the ground truth with a user-specified probability, such as 90%. It is easy-to-understand, easy-to-use, and general, applying naturally to problems arising in the fields of computer vision, natural language processing, deep reinforcement learning, and so on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mathematical aspects of data drift in machine learning</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/data_drift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/projects/data_drift/</guid><description>&lt;p>Data drift is a common problem in machine learning where the statistical properties of the data used for model training change over time. This can lead to a drop in model performance, as the model is no longer optimized for the new distribution of data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Data drift can occur for many reasons, such as changes in the data collection process, changes in user behavior, or changes in the underlying system being modeled. To mitigate data drift, it is important to monitor the performance of the model over time and retrain it with updated data when necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several techniques that can be used to detect and address data drift, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Monitoring key performance metrics such as accuracy, precision, and recall over time to detect drops in model performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using statistical tests to compare the distributions of the data used for training and testing the model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using data augmentation techniques such as synthetic data generation to supplement the training data and make the model more robust to changes in the data distribution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Employing domain adaptation techniques to adapt the model to new data distributions, while minimizing the need for retraining the entire model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By proactively monitoring and addressing data drift, machine learning models can maintain high levels of accuracy and continue to provide valuable insights even as data distribution changes over time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Machine Learning</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/teaching/2023_2024/winter/machine_learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/teaching/2023_2024/winter/machine_learning/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="course-summary">&lt;strong>Course Summary&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course provides a broad introduction to machine learning and statistical pattern recognition with the main focus on the deep learning methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Time and Location&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Winter Term, 2023/2024&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thursday 1:15 PM - 3:00 PM, &lt;em>C13, A.1.13&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Grading &amp;amp; Rules&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The course is divided into two streams. Namely, in-class lectures and labs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In total, a student can obtain up to &lt;strong>50&lt;/strong> points.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The maximum number of points that can be achieved for labs is &lt;strong>34&lt;/strong> points.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A student can get additional &lt;strong>16&lt;/strong> points from the oral exam that will take place during the examination session.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To obtain a positive mark it is sufficient and necessary to obtain at least &lt;strong>25&lt;/strong> points
total. Then, the final grade is calculated as follows:
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align:center">&lt;div style="width:140px"> POINTS &lt;/div>&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:center">&lt;div style="width:140px"> GRADE &lt;/div>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">[25, 30)&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">3.0&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">[30, 35)&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">3.5&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">[35, 40)&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">4.0&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">[40, 45)&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">4.5&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">[45, 50]&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">5.0&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;br/>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Syllabus&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>EVENT&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:center">&lt;div style="width:140px"> DATE &lt;/div>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>LECTURE&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:center">MATERIALS&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 1&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">05/10/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Topics:&lt;/strong>&lt;br>- Class introduction &lt;br>- Course details&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">No materials&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 2&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">12/10/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Topics:&lt;/strong>&lt;br>- Machine Learning introduction&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 3&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">19/10/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Topics:&lt;/strong>&lt;br>- Supervised Learning&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">TBP&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 4&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">26/10/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 5&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">09/11/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 6&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">16/11/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 7&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">23/11/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 8&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">30/11/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 9&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">07/12/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 10&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">14/12/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 11&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">21/12/2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 12&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">11/01/2024&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 13&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">18/01/2024&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 14&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">25/01/2024&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Lecture 15&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">01/02/2024&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBA&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Materials&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hastie, T., Tibshirani, R.,, Friedman, J. (2001). &lt;strong>The Elements of Statistical Learning&lt;/strong>. New York, NY, USA: Springer New York Inc.. &lt;a href="https://hastie.su.domains/Papers/ESLII.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PDF Version&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Goodfellow, I., Bengio, Y., &amp;amp; Courville, A. (2016). &lt;strong>Deep learning&lt;/strong>. MIT Press. &lt;a href="https://www.deeplearningbook.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Online Version&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Welcome to Wowchemy, the website builder for Hugo</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/post/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/post/getting-started/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The Wowchemy website builder for Hugo, along with its starter templates, is designed for professional creators, educators, and teams/organizations - although it can be used to create any kind of site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The template can be modified and customised to suit your needs. It&amp;rsquo;s a good platform for anyone looking to take control of their data and online identity whilst having the convenience to start off with a &lt;strong>no-code solution (write in Markdown and customize with YAML parameters)&lt;/strong> and having &lt;strong>flexibility to later add even deeper personalization with HTML and CSS&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can work with all your favourite tools and apps with hundreds of plugins and integrations to speed up your workflows, interact with your readers, and much more&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/main/starters/academic/preview.png" alt="The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device." loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="get-started">Get Started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ðŸ‘‰ &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/templates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;strong>Create a new site&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ“š &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;strong>Personalize your site&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ’¬ &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chat with the &lt;strong>Wowchemy community&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://discourse.gohugo.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;strong>Hugo community&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ¦ Twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wowchemy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@wowchemy&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@GeorgeCushen&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23MadeWithWowchemy&amp;amp;src=typed_query" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#MadeWithWowchemy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ’¡ &lt;a href="https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-themes/issues" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Request a &lt;strong>feature&lt;/strong> or report a &lt;strong>bug&lt;/strong> for &lt;em>Wowchemy&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>â¬†ï¸ &lt;strong>Updating Wowchemy?&lt;/strong> View the &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/hugo-tutorials/update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Update Tutorial&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/updates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Release Notes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="crowd-funded-open-source-software">Crowd-funded open-source software&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To help us develop this template and software sustainably under the MIT license, we ask all individuals and businesses that use it to help support its ongoing maintenance and development via sponsorship.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="-click-here-to-become-a-sponsor-and-help-support-wowchemys-future-httpswowchemycomsponsor">&lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/sponsor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">â¤ï¸ Click here to become a sponsor and help support Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s future â¤ï¸&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As a token of appreciation for sponsoring, you can &lt;strong>unlock &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/sponsor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">these&lt;/a> awesome rewards and extra features ðŸ¦„âœ¨&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ecosystem">Ecosystem&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://github.com/wowchemy/hugo-academic-cli" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hugo Academic CLI&lt;/a>:&lt;/strong> Automatically import publications from BibTeX&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="inspiration">Inspiration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://academic-demo.netlify.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Check out the latest &lt;strong>demo&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/user-stories/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">view the &lt;strong>showcase&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> of personal, project, and business sites.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Page builder&lt;/strong> - Create &lt;em>anything&lt;/em> with &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/page-builder/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;strong>widgets&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;strong>elements&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Edit any type of content&lt;/strong> - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create content&lt;/strong> in &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;strong>Markdown&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/import/jupyter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;strong>Jupyter&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/install-locally/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;strong>RStudio&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plugin System&lt;/strong> - Fully customizable &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;strong>color&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>font themes&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display Code and Math&lt;/strong> - Code highlighting and &lt;a href="https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LaTeX math&lt;/a> supported&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Integrations&lt;/strong> - &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Analytics&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://disqus.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Disqus commenting&lt;/a>, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Beautiful Site&lt;/strong> - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong> - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Media Galleries&lt;/strong> - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong> - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Multi-language&lt;/strong> - 34+ language packs including English, ä¸­æ–‡, and PortuguÃªs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Multi-user&lt;/strong> - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Privacy Pack&lt;/strong> - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Stand Out&lt;/strong> - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong> - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="themes">Themes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Wowchemy and its templates come with &lt;strong>automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong> built-in. Alternatively, visitors can choose their preferred mode - click the moon icon in the top right of the &lt;a href="https://academic-demo.netlify.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Demo&lt;/a> to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in &lt;code>params.toml&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Choose a stunning &lt;strong>theme&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>font&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for your site. Themes are fully customizable.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="license">License&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href="https://georgecushen.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">George Cushen&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Released under the &lt;a href="https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-themes/blob/master/LICENSE.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MIT&lt;/a> license.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Slides</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/slides/example/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/slides/example/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy">Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wowchemy&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports speaker notes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="controls">Controls&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Next: &lt;code>Right Arrow&lt;/code> or &lt;code>Space&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Previous: &lt;code>Left Arrow&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start: &lt;code>Home&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finish: &lt;code>End&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Overview: &lt;code>Esc&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speaker notes: &lt;code>S&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fullscreen: &lt;code>F&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zoom: &lt;code>Alt + Click&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PDF Export&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="code-highlighting">Code Highlighting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Inline code: &lt;code>variable&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Code block:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="n">porridge&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span> &lt;span class="s2">&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">if&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">porridge&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">==&lt;/span> &lt;span class="s2">&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> &lt;span class="nb">print&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">(&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s2">&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">)&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="math">Math&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Block math:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="fragments">Fragments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Press &lt;code>Space&lt;/code> to play!&lt;/p>
&lt;span class="fragment " >
One
&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="fragment " >
&lt;strong>Two&lt;/strong>
&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="fragment " >
Three
&lt;/span>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>class&lt;/code>: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>weight&lt;/code>: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="speaker-notes">Speaker Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">-&lt;/span> Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">-&lt;/span> Press &lt;span class="sb">`S`&lt;/span> key to view
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Press the &lt;code>S&lt;/code> key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="notes">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press &lt;code>S&lt;/code> key to view&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/aside>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="themes">Themes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
data-background-image="/media/boards.jpg"
>
&lt;h2 id="custom-slide">Custom Slide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{&lt;span class="p">&amp;lt;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">slide&lt;/span> &lt;span class="na">background-image&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">&amp;gt;&lt;/span>}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{&lt;span class="p">&amp;lt;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">slide&lt;/span> &lt;span class="na">background-color&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">&amp;gt;&lt;/span>}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{&lt;span class="p">&amp;lt;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">slide&lt;/span> &lt;span class="na">class&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">&amp;gt;&lt;/span>}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="custom-css-example">Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Create &lt;code>assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code> with:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-css" data-lang="css">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="nc">reveal&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">section&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">h1&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="nc">reveal&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">section&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">h2&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="nc">reveal&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">section&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">h3&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> &lt;span class="k">color&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span> &lt;span class="kc">navy&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="questions">Questions?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ask&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An example conference paper</title><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/publication/example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/publication/example/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Click the &lt;em>Cite&lt;/em> button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em>Slides&lt;/em> button to check out the example.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">code, math, and images&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dkucharc.github.io/academic/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>